Hitarth Bhatt

IOS DEVELOPER

 I +91 8302880263
 I I hitarthbhatt12@gmail.com
 I Portfolio
 I Github
 I Linkedin

Personal Profile

3.5+ Years of experience in developing and designing iOS, iPadOS, and watchOS applications. I'm always passionate about developing a fast and reliable application. Throughout my carrier, I've developed applications from scratch to release, Implement enhanced features in big projects.

Skills_

Concepts Data Structures, OOPS, Multi threading, MVC, MVVM - C, RESTful APIs, App Store Publishing.

Language & Tools Swift, C++, Objective C, Xcode, Git, JIRA, SourceTree, CocoaPods, Swift Package Manager, Charles.

Frameworks & Library SwiftUI, UIKit, Combine, Firebase, Swift Charts, Concurrency, CoreData, StreamChat, 100MS.

Work Experience_

Walmart Global Tech (Walmart App)

Bangalore, India

Software Engineer III

Mar 2024 - Present

- Enhanced Walmart e-Commerce item pages as part of the Apparel team, improving customer experience.
- Integrating Bazel Build for faster iOS build.
- Implemented Complete the Look feature to boost cross-selling and customer engagement.
- Introduced **Dynamic size guide** to reduce return rates with personalized size recommendations.

Adobe Systems (via Hughes Systique Corporation) (PSX App)

Noida, India

iOS Developer

Apr 2023 - Mar 2024

- Valuable contributor to the growth team for a popular photo editor Adobe PSX with millions of users, maintaining an impressive 4.8 rating from around 700K users
- · Implemented data-driven strategies and UX enhancements, resulting in a 15% boost in user engagement and a 20% decrease in churn rate
- · Worked on user paywall and In-App Messaging infrastructure
- Ensured seamless light and dark theme support throughout the app.
- Initiated experiments with A/B variants in different countries, using Adobe Analytics to elevate successful variants to global features.
- Developed a **Python script** to establish an A/B infrastructure for languages localisation.

Simform Solutions (AI-Health App)

Ahmedabad, India

iOS Developer

Jul 2021 - Feb 2023

- Working on Fitness application which works over Apple devices (iPad, iPhone, watchOS).
- · Working with 5 person's team in a remote environment and providing fast deliveries of new features.
- Revamped legacy codebase by implementing **MVVM architecture** and integrating **SwiftUI** framework, resulting in a 40% reduction in app crashes and improved user experience.
- Refactor more than 80% watchOS screens to SwiftUI framework.

Projects _____

SSLineChart (Link)

Ahmedabad, India

Open Source Project

- · Developed an open-source library exclusively for watchOS, offering the unique capability to create gradient-based line charts in Swift.
- Implemented functionality for drawing gradient elements, meeting the demand for visually appealing data representation on watchOS platforms.

Education

Arya College Of Engineering And IT

laipur, India

BTech in Information Technology (7.1 CGPA)

2017 - 2021

Certificate & Achievements

Present **Leetcode**, Solved **200+** data structure and algorithm problems

Link

Dec 2019 **Udemy**, The Complete iOS App Development Bootcamp

Link

Oct 2019 University of Toronto, Introduction To Swift Programming

Link